Guide to the New York University Archives Collection of Student Handbooks MC.301
New York University Archives
New York University Archives Collection of Student Handbooks
1854-2009
New York University Archives
New York University
MC.301
12 Linear Feet in 24 manuscript boxes
This collection contains student handbooks from schools within New York University dating from 1854 to 2009. The early handbooks cover the university in its entirety, but later are often school- and program-specific.
Conditions Governing Access
Materials are open without restrictions.
Arrangement
Items are arranged at the folder level. The handbooks are arranged first by their Record Group (based on school or program) and then chronologically within that RG.
Scope and Contents
This collection contains student handbooks dating from 1854 to 2009 generated by New York University and its component schools. These handbooks gave students information on services provided by the school, resources for student life, and student activities at NYU. It also contains guidebooks for financial aid, dormitories, and conducting research.
Historical Note
The earliest handbooks from the collection date from the 1850s and touch upon subjects such as student behavior and locations of university buildings. Later handbooks were published for specific schools and specific programs within these schools.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Materials found in collection; provenance is unknown for the bulk of materials. 1928-1928 edition of The Waverly is the gift of Mark A. Goldstein, 2018. An accretion was added in 2022.
Student activities.; Handbooks.
- All-University student handbooks (RG 1), 1854, 1897-1902, 1915-1916, circa 1950s, 1983-1988 (Box 1)
- All-University student handbooks (RG 1), 1988-2000 (Box 2)
- All-University student handbooks (RG 1), 2000-2009 (Box 3)
- Student Guide to Cross-School Advisement and Registration (RG 1.0), 1990-1991 (Box 24, Folder 1)
- University Heights (Palisades) student handbooks (RG 18), 1926-1931 (Box 3)
- University Heights (Palisades) student handbooks (RG 18), 1931-1942 (Box 4)
- University Heights (Palisades) student handbooks (RG 18), 1942-1943, 1945-1959 (Box 5)
- University Heights (Palisades) student handbooks (RG 18), 1961-1971 (Box 6)
- University Heights (Palisades) student handbooks (RG 18), 1971-1973 (Box 7)
- Washington Square College (The Waverly) student handbooks (RG 19), 1922, 1927-1932, 1938-1943 (Box 7)
- Washington Square College student handbooks (RG 19), 1947-1948, 1951-1958, 1960-1967, 1969-1974 (Box 8)
  Scope and Contents
  Includes Weinstein Residence Halls handbook (1966-1967).
- Washington Square College student handbooks (RG 19), 1974-1983 (Box 9)
- Washington Square College (College of Arts and Science) student handbooks (RG 19), 1983-1984, 1995-2000, 2003-2004, 2006 (Box 10)
- Washington Square College (Handbook for the Evening Division) student handbooks (RG 19.13), 1930-1934, 1938-1943, 1947-1949 (Box 10)
- Washington Square College (Graduate School of Arts and Science) student handbooks (RG 20), 1975-1976, 1978, 1987-1988, 1991, 1994 (Box 11)
- School of Law student handbooks (RG 22), 1953-1954, circa 1960s, 1968-1970, circa 1970s, 1973-1976 (Box 11)
- School of Law student handbooks (RG 22), 1976-1992 (Box 12)
- School of Law student handbooks (RG 22), 1992-1994, 1996-1998 (Box 13)
- School of Medicine student handbooks (RG 23), 1898-1899, 1945, 1978 (Box 13)
- College of Engineering student handbooks (RG 24), 1932-1933 (Box 13)
- College of Dentistry student handbooks (RG 25), 1965-1970, 1973-1976 (Box 14)
- College of Dentistry student handbooks (RG 25), 1977-1981 (Box 15)
- College of Dentistry student handbooks (RG 25), 1981-1984 (Box 16)
- College of Dentistry student handbooks (RG 25), 1983-1993 (Box 17)
- College of Dentistry student handbooks (RG 25), 1992-1996, 1998-2003 (Box 18)
- School of Education student handbooks (RG 26), 1931-1932, 1937, 1939, 1940-1942 (Box 18)
- School of Education student handbooks (RG 26), 1944-1945, 1947-1948, 1950-1972, circa 1962-1963, circa 1965-1972 (Box 19)
- School of Education student handbooks (RG 26), 1971-1974 (Box 20)
- School of Education, Health, Nursing, and Arts Professions student handbooks (RG 26), 1975-1977, 1980-1981, 1986, 1990-1991, 1991-1997, 1993-2001, 2000-2002 (Box 20)
- Steinhardt School of Education student handbooks (RG 26), 2003-2004 (Box 20)
- School of Education (Study Abroad) student handbooks (RG 26.28), 1991-1997, 1993-2001, circa 2000s (Box 20)
- School of Education (Study Abroad) student handbooks (RG 26.28), 1998-2003, 2003-2007 (Box 21)
- School of Commerce student handbooks (RG 27), 1932-1935, 1937-1938, 1941-1943 (Box 21)
- School of Commerce student handbooks (RG 27), 1946-1947, 1949-1950, 1952-1956 (Box 22)
- College of Business and Public Administration student handbooks (RG 27), 1972-1977, 1979-1988, 1990-1991 (Box 22)
- Graduate School of Business Administration student handbooks (RG 28), 1962, 1971-1974 (Box 22)
- Graduate School of Business Administration student handbooks (RG 28), 1976, 1979, 1981-1982 (Box 23)
- School of Continuing Education student handbooks (RG 32), 1979-1981, 1984-1985, circa 1980s (Box 23)
- Graduate School of Public Administration student handbooks (RG 33), 1977 (Box 23)
- School of Social Work student handbooks (RG 34), 1980-1981 (Box 23)
- School of the Arts student handbooks (RG 35), 1977-1978, 1981-1982 (Box 23)
- Tisch School of the Arts student handbooks (RG 35), 1995-1996 (Box 23)
- Gallatin Division student handbooks (RG 36), 1975-1978, 1981-1985 (Box 23)
- Elmer Holmes Bobst Library student handbooks (RG 38.1), 1973 (Box 23, Box Shared University Archives 073)
- Program Board/Film Committee (RG 39.60)
  - Unprocessed materials (Box Shared University Archives 077)
- WSC/WSUC/CAS Student Council (RG 44.2)
  - Course Evaluation Handbook, 1979-1991 (Box 24, Folder 3-6)